Guide to the Herbert Matter Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series 9: Photographs Gifted from the Matter Family, 1.5 linear ft.
  - Subseries 9.01: Abstracts
    - Amoeba forms; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667318; 8"x15 3/4": Matted Marked on back in pencil "Top" (Othertype 407, Folder 12)
    - Layered water movement; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667326; 11"x14": Marked on back in pencil "8" (Othertype 407, Folder 13)
    - Rock forms with water in the center; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667334; 9"x14" (Othertype 407, Folder 14)
    - Dark colored rock forms with water in the center; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667342; 9"x14" (Othertype 407, Folder 15)
    - Two forms: One elliptical; one round; On white background with light shadow; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667359; 11"x14" (Othertype 407, Folder 16)
    - Close up of rocks; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667367; 8 1/2"x91/4" (Othertype 407, Folder 17)
    - Close up of bark on dark background; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667375; 8 1/2"x9 1/2" (Othertype 407, Folder 18)
    - Two dominant membrane-like forms; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667383; 8 1/2"x11": Stamped on back "Studio Associates" and "Herbert Matter" (Othertype 407, Folder 19)
    - Water form with clouds; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667391; 11"x14" (Othertype 407, Folder 20)
    - Multiple white wavelet forms; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667409; 16"x20" (Othertype 407, Folder 21)
    - Rock form close up on sand; [Folder 1].ND, 36105115667417; 16"x20" (Othertype 407, Folder 22)
    - "Cabbage (solarized), 1943; [Folder 1]."1943 ca., 36105115667425; 16"x20". Marked in pencil on back handwritten "7" circled: "top": "Herbert Matter": MacDougal Alley address. (Othertype 407, Folder 23)
    - Closeup of ice cube; [Folder 1]; Early Swiss image.ND, 36105115667581; 6 1/4"x9" (Othertype 407, Folder 24)
    - "Stylized folded rippled fabric; From 8"x10" plate negative; [Folder 1]."ND, 36105115667599; 8"x10" (Othertype 407, Folder 25)
    - "'Light drawing, 1943"; [Folder 1]."1943 ca., 36105115667607; 16"x20": Written on back in pencil "3". (Othertype 407, Folder 26)
  - Subseries 9.02: Biographical
    - Matter studio interior only; with draped mannequin with blind fold; [Folder 1]., 36105115666237; 6 1/2"x9" (Othertype 400, Folder 1)
    - Hebert Matter looking at Giacometti sculpture; [Folder 1]., 36105115666245; 8"x10" (Othertype 400, Folder 2)
    - Herbert Matter with cigarette in mouth; camera in hand and seagulls in background; 1937; [Folder 1].1937, 36105115666252; 8"x83/4" (Othertype 400, Folder 3)
    - Matter family with Charles and Ray Eames on the beach; 1943; [Folder 1].1943, 36105115666260; 8"x10": Contact print of 2 1/4" negatives (b/w 12 images). (Othertype 400, Folder 4)
    - Herbert Matter in stripped shirt with cigarette in mouth working with large mounted camera; Angle is seen from below; 1960; [Folder 1].1960 ca., 36105115667102; 8"x10": written in pencil on back is "1577-0". (Othertype 400, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 9.03: Calder, Alexander
    - Alexander Calder Toy Figures; [Folder 2]., 36105115664836; 11"x14": In Matter's handwriting on back in ink "p.82 74% Toy by Alexander Calder photo: Herbert Matter" (Othertype 400, Folder 1)
    - Early Calder studio; assorted wires; Ca; late 1930s; [Folder 2].ND, 36105115664844; 11"x14": Stamped on back "Herbert Matter". (Othertype 400, Folder 2)
    - Alexander Calder hanging mobile; [Folder 2]., 36105115664851; 11"x14": Stamped on back "Herbert Matter". (Othertype 400, Folder 3)
    - Alexander Calder hand sculpture; [Folder 2]., 36105115664869; 11"x14": Stamped on back "Herbert Matter". (Othertype 400, Folder 4)
    - Alexander Calder circus figures; [Folder 2]., 36105115664877; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 5)
    - Alexander Calder whale sculpture at MoMA; [Folder 2]., 36105115664885; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 6)
    - Alexander Calder Stabile; "The Spider"; [Folder 2]., 36105115664893; 9 1/2"x91/4": In Matter's handwriting on back in pencil is the title date: material of sculpture and Matter's McDougal address. (Othertype 400, Folder 7)
    - Alexander Calder hanging a sculpture; [Folder 2].1938, 36105115664901; 11"x14": Marked on back "Alexander Calder photo: Hebert Matter". (Othertype 400, Folder 8)
    - Alexander Calder with circus arrangement; [Folder 2]., 36105115664919; 11"x14": Marked on back "57% p.42". (Othertype 400, Folder 9)
    - Alexander Calder playing with his children; Louisa playing accordion; [Folder 2]., 36105115664927; 11"x14": Marked on back "58% p.73". (Othertype 400, Folder 10)
    - Louisa Calder with textiles; [Folder 2]., 36105115664935; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 11)
    - Alexander Calder plexiglas sculpture; [Folder 2].1939, 36105115664943; 8"x10" (Othertype 400, Folder 12)
    - Alexander Calder metal face sculpture; [Folder 2]., 36105115664950; 8"x10" (Othertype 400, Folder 13)
    - Alexander Calder wire animal; [Folder 2]., 36105115664968; 8"x10": Stamped on back "Herbert Matter". (Othertype 400, Folder 14)
    - Alexander Calder wire bird on wheels sculpture; [Folder 2]., 36105115664976; 8"x10": Stamped on back "Herbert Matter". (Othertype 400, Folder 15)
    - Alexander Calder Stabile with shadow; [Folder 2]., 36105115664984; 8"x10": Stamped on back "Studio Associates" and "Herbert Matter". (Othertype 400, Folder 16)
    - Alexander Calder portrait; close up; [Folder 2].1950, 36105115664992; 16"x20" (Othertype 400, Folder 17)
    - Alexander Calder with Louisa portrait outside;[Folder 2].1940, 36105115665007; 16"x20" (Othertype 400, Folder 18)
    - Alexander Calder working with wire; [Folder 2].1936, 36105115665015; 16"x20" (Othertype 400, Folder 19)
    - Alexander Calder studio interior with desk and mail; [Folder 2].1950, 36105115666229; 8"x10": Stamped on back "Studio Associates" and "Herbert Matter" (Othertype 400, Folder 20)
    - Alexander Calder sculpture (arp-like). [Folder 2].1950, 36105115667532; 9 3/4"x12 3/4": Stamped on back "Photo" and "Herbert Matter" (Othertype 400, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 9.04: Fashion
    - Model with street vendor in South America; [Folder 3].ND, 36105115665882; 8"x9": Marked on back "credit Herbert Matter from Black Star" with "720". (Othertype 400, Folder 1)
    - Model with hat and veil off to the side looking off to her shoulder; [Folder 3].ND, 36105115665890; 8"x9 1/2": Stamped on back "Herbert Matter". (Othertype 400, Folder 2)
    - Model with hat and veil off to the side looking into the camera;[Folder 3].ND, 36105115666104; 10 1/2"x12" (Othertype 400, Folder 3)
    - Model wearing coral in hair; with experimental photographic effect;[Folder 3].ND, 36105115666112; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 4)
    - Model at the beach in the water with white swimsuit; out stretched arms seen from above; From series for Life magazine; [Folder 3].1937 June 28, 36105115666120; 8"x10" (Othertype 400, Folder 5)
    - Model in swimsuit floating on her back; [Folder 3]., 36105115665908; 8"x10" (Othertype 400, Folder 6)
    - Jewelry design; [Folder 3]., 36105115665916; 8"x10": Stamped on back "Studio Associates" and "Herbert Matter" (Othertype 400, Folder 7)
    - Models (woman and two men) in carriage view from above; [Folder 3]., 36105115665924; 8"x10": Marked on back "credit Herbert Matter from Black Star" with "397" and "couple outdoor romance". (Othertype 400, Folder 8)
    - Close of model's face; [Folder 3]., 36105115665932; 8"x10" (Othertype 400, Folder 9)
    - Model trimming decorative lawn hedge; [Folder 3].ND, 36105115665940; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 10)
    - Model running along water at the beach; [Folder 3]., 36105115665957; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 11)
    - Model with towel (studio shot); [Folder 3]., 36105115665965; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 12)
    - Close up of model's face with dark hair and light features; [Folder 3]., 36105115665973; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 13)
    - Close up of model's face with light hair and light background; [Folder 3].ND, 36105115665981; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 14)
    - Model in full length gown with matching head cover and in outdoor setting; [Folder 3]., 36105115665999; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 15)
    - "Four model's (three dancing) in park like setting; "Fete Champetre" from: The Art and Technique of Color Photography; Simon and Schuster; New York; 1951; Page 150-151; [Folder 3]."ND, 36105115666005; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 16)
    - Model in profile view; "Woman with beads, ca. 1948"; [Folder 3]."1948 ca., 36105115666013; 11"x14" (Othertype 400, Folder 17)
    - Fabric in circular motion; [Folder 3].1948 Feb. 5, 36105115612132; 11"x14": Stamped on back "Matter Vogue Studios": written in pencil "15572-0-02". (Othertype 400, Folder 18)
    - Female model with bicycles; [Folder 3].ND, 36105115667516; 8"x10". (Othertype 400, Folder 19)
    - Fashion experiment with model; Vertical white curves across face; [Folder 3].1948 ca., 36105115667524; 15 3/4"x19 3/4" (Othertype 400, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 9.05: Giacometti, Alberto
    - Sculpture of man's head with gray background (different): "Head of a Man on a Rod; 1947"., 36105115665031; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 1)
    - Sculpture of man's head; neck and upper shoulder with face in opposite direction: "Bust of Elie Lotar II; 1965"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Black and white image of color print; page 186-187., 36105115665064; 16"x20": Signed on front in pencil: "Herbert Matter". (Othertype 402, Folder 2)
    - Sculpture of a hand: "Hand; 1947"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Cropped print; page 68-69., 36105115665072; 12"x16" (Othertype 402, Folder 3)
    - Sculpture of man sitting: "Bust of Elie Lotar III; 1965"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Page 190., 36105115665080; 113/4"x16" (Othertype 402, Folder 4)
    - Sculpture of man sitting (reduced printed image): "Bust of Elie Lotar III; 1965"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Page 190., 36105115665098; 12 1/2"x16" (Othertype 402, Folder 5)
    - Sculpture of man's head extreme close up on dark background: "Bust of Elie Lotar II; 1965"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Black and white image of color print; page 188., 36105115665106; 14"x173/4" (Othertype 402, Folder 6)
    - Sculpture of man full figure: unidentified sculpture standing figure on base., 36105115665114; 33/4"x14": Marked on back in ink "2. 1958-59 h 64cm". (Othertype 402, Folder 7)
    - Sculpture of woman's body full figure: "Woman; 1956"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Uncropped print; page 103., 36105115665122; 5 1/2"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 8)
    - Sculpture of woman's head close up in soft focus: "Annette IV 1962"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Printed variation; page 179., 36105115665130; 11"x16" (Othertype 402, Folder 9)
    - Sculpture of a man's head close up soft focus: studio interior; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Page 33., 36105115665148; 151/4"x17": Mounted on board. (Othertype 402, Folder 10)
    - Interior Giacometti studio with sculpture in center: studio interior, 36105115665155; 15 1/2"x17": Mounted on board. (Othertype 402, Folder 11)
    - Interior Giacometti studio with wrapped sculpture in center; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Different angle from studio interior Page 31., 36105115665163; 81/4"x93/4": Stamped on back "Herbert Matter"Marked on back "14-329". (Othertype 402, Folder 12)
    - Photograph of painting: "Seated Woman; 1959;" Oil on canvas., 36105115665171; 16"x20": Marked on back "Giacometti: Head of a woman 1959: oil on canvas 29 1/2 x 24" Galleria Galatea: Turin photograph Herbert Matter". (Othertype 402, Folder 13)
    - Photograph of painting: "Annette Seated II; 1958"; Oil on canvas; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Black and white variation of color print; page 145., 36105115665189; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 14)
    - Sculpture with four figures: "Four Women on a Base; 1950"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Black and white variation of color print; page 78-79, 36105115665197; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 15)
    - Photograph of painting: "Head; 1961"; Oil on canvas., 36105115665205; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 16)
    - "Sculpture with nine figures: "Women of Venice, 1956".", 36105115665213; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 17)
    - "Sculpture with woman's head close up: "Woman, 1956"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Printed variation; page 103.", 36105115665221; 16"x20". (Othertype 402, Folder 18)
    - "Sculpture with man's head close up: "Diego, 1952"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Black and white variation of color print; page 98-99.", 36105115665239; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 19)
    - "Sculpture with nine figures in 3/4 view: "Large Standing Woman I, II, III, IV, 1960".", 36105115665247; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 20)
    - "Sculpture with man's head and neck close up: "Bust of Elie Lotar II, 1965"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Black and white variation of color print; page 191.", 36105115665254; 16"x20". (Othertype 402, Folder 21)
    - Sculpture with man walking profile: "Men Walking; 1950"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Printed variation; page 74-75, 36105115665262; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 22)
    - Sculpture with nine figures; alternating exposures on each figure: "Large Standing Woman I; II; III; IV; 1960"., 36105115665270; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 23)
    - "Sculpture with two images side by side one full view the other profile: "Bust of Diego, 1954"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Page 110-111.", 36105115665288; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 24)
    - "Sculpture of man's head and neck; upper shoulder: "Diego, 1952".", 36105115665296; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 25)
    - "Sculpture of woman with short hair: "Annette IV, 1962"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Printed variation page 179.", 36105115665304; 16"x20". (Othertype 402, Folder 26)
    - "Sculpture of man with exaggerated perspective to right: "Head of a Man on a rod, 1947"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Printed variation and angle; page 66-67.", 36105115665312; 16"x20". (Othertype 402, Folder 27)
    - "Sculpture with eight figures (distorted): "The Forest, 1950"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Printed variation page 86-87.", 36105115665320; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 28)
    - Sculpture of man's head with gray background: "Head of a Man on a Rod; 1947"., 36105115665338; 16"x20": Marked on back in pencil "1947". (Othertype 402, Folder 29)
    - Exterior of Giacometti studio; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Page 27., 36105115665346; 16"x20" (Othertype 402, Folder 30)
    - "Sculpture with eight figures (distorted; different perspective): "The Forest, 1950"; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Different angle and cropping; Page 86-87.", 36105115665353; 16"x20": Signed on front in ink: "Herbert Matter #6 25/50". (Othertype 402, Folder 31)
    - Exterior entry stairs of Giacometti studio., 36105115665361; 11"x14": Marked on back in pencil "13-299". (Othertype 402, Folder 32)
    - Close up of Giacometti name on exterior Studio door., 36105115665379; 11"x14": Marked on back in pencil "13-298". (Othertype 402, Folder 33)
    - Isaku Yanihara with dark background., 36105115665387; 11"x14": Marked on back in pencil "16-372". (Othertype 402, Folder 34)
    - "Giacometti farm house exterior; Stampa, Switzerland; Giacometti parent's home.", 36105115665395; 11"x14": Marked on back in pencil "9-200". (Othertype 402, Folder 35)
    - "Landscape; trees; Stampa, Switzerland.", 36105115665403; 11"x14": Marked on back in pencil "7-146". (Othertype 402, Folder 36)
    - Landscape; mountains around Julier Pass near Stampa; Switzerland., 36105115665411; 11"x14": Marked on back in pencil "10-236". (Othertype 402, Folder 37)
    - Street entrance to Giacometti studio; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Different angle and cropping; Print variation; close cropping; Page 27., 36105115665429; 11"x14": Marked on back in in "13-295". (Othertype 402, Folder 38)
    - Single sculpture full figure: "Standing Woman; 1948"., 36105115665437; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "1948". (Othertype 402, Folder 39)
    - Giacometti portrait; 1965; 3/4 profile with vignette frame; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Similar to image; page 2., 36105115665445; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 40)
    - Single unidentified figure standing on base; Full figure with background out of focus., 36105115665452; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "12-281". (Othertype 402, Folder 41)
    - Sculpture of man walking profile view with light background: "Man Walking; 1950"., 36105115665460; 11"x14": Marked on back in red ink "849/858/859". (Othertype 402, Folder 42)
    - Painting of man from the neck up: "Head of Diego; 1961"; Oil on canvas., 36105115665478; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "24". (Othertype 402, Folder 43)
    - "Painting of man from the neck up (different figure): "Head, 1961"; Oil on canvas.", 36105115665486; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "32". (Othertype 402, Folder 44)
    - "Painting of man from the neck up different background; Yanaihara, Isaku; 1960; Oil on canvas.", 36105115665494; 11"x14": Marked on back in green ink "1957". (Othertype 402, Folder 45)
    - "3/4 view of grouped sculptures on black background: "The Forest, 1950".", 36105115665502; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 46)
    - "3/4 view of grouped sculptures on white background: "The Forest, 1950".", 36105115665510; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 47)
    - Sculpture of man walking back view with long shadow on light background., 36105115665528; 11"x14": Marked on back in green ink "1950". (Othertype 402, Folder 48)
    - 3/4 view of wrapped sculpture with sculpture in background., 36105115665536; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 49)
    - "Painting of a woman: "Seated Woman, 1962"; Oil on canvas.", 36105115665544; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 50)
    - Wrapped sculpture with photographic effect; Studio interior., 36105115665551; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 51)
    - Four sculpture figures on dark gray background., 36105115665569; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 52)
    - Sculptures in museum setting., 36105115665577; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 53)
    - Three sculptures in museum setting., 36105115665585; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 54)
    - Two groups of sculptures in a museum setting., 36105115665593; 11"x14" (Othertype 402, Folder 55)
    - Interior Giacometti studio cigarette packs., 36105115665601; 11"x14": Marked on back in pencil "29-27". (Othertype 402, Folder 56)
    - Interior Giacometti studio stove., 36105115665619; 11"x14": Stamped on back "Herbert Matter": Marked on back in pencil "17-395". (Othertype 402, Folder 57)
    - Interior Giacometti studio with cigarette packs and sculpture., 36105115665627; 11"x14": Marked on back in pencil "14-323". (Othertype 402, Folder 58)
    - Unidentified sculpture with three figures walking in different directions on signed pedestal base "A. Gacometti"., 36105115665635; 11"x14": Signed on back in "Matter". (Othertype 402, Folder 59)
    - "Four sculpture figures with gray background: "Four Women on a Base, 1950".", 36105115665643; 11"x14": Stamped on back "Studio Associates" and "Herbert Matter "Marked on back in ink "#21". (Othertype 402, Folder 60)
    - Sculpture of man's head cast; white background: "Bust of Diego" undated., 36105115665650; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "23-522". (Othertype 402, Folder 61)
    - "Painting of a woman from the neck up: "Seated Woman, 1959"; Oil on canvas.", 36105115665668; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "30". (Othertype 402, Folder 62)
    - "Four sculpture figures on dark background: "Four Women on a Base, 1950".", 36105115665676; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "1950". (Othertype 402, Folder 63)
    - Unidentified sculpture of woman standing in profile with base., 36105115665684; 11"x14": Marked on back in green ink "1954". (Othertype 402, Folder 64)
    - Sculpture in exterior entry way of Giacometti studio with sculpture., 36105115665692; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "22-504". (Othertype 402, Folder 65)
    - Wrapped sculpture in studio side view., 36105115665700; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "14-331". (Othertype 402, Folder 66)
    - Giacometti at work on a sculpture wearing a coat and tie; 1960; From the book: Alberto Giacometti / photographed by Herbert Matter; text by Mercedes Matter; foreword by Louis Finkelstein; with an introduction by Andrew Forge; New York: Abrams; 1987; Similar to image; page 46., 36105115665718; 11"x14": Marked on back in ink "34-26". (Othertype 402, Folder 67)